爷爷！
Grandpa!
这些木头够你用一整天了！
You have enough wood here for the whole day!
爷爷！
Grandpa!
我知道你是谁
I know who you are.
你就是…
You're the inspector who...
逮捕那个疯子的督察
arrested that lunatic, that butcher.
- 是的 - 恭喜，干得好
- I am. - Congratulations. Well done.
爷爷，你真的知道我是谁吗？
Grandpa, do you know who I really am?
我知道
I know.
你是普莱蒂科西奇督察
You're inspector Pletikosich.
是的，我是普莱蒂科西奇督察
Yes, I'm inspector Pletikosich.
你知道你也姓普莱蒂科西奇吗？
Do you know you're also Pletikosich?
你知道我们住在一起吗？
Do you know we live here together?
你知道我为什么叫你爷爷吗？
Do you know why I call you grandpa?
我跟你说话的时候请看着我
Please, look at me when I'm talking to you.
你知道我们住在一起吗？
Do you know we live here together?
你知道我们是一家人吗？
Do you know we have the same last name?
你知道我为什么叫你爷爷吗
And do you know why I call you grandpa
回答我？
Tell me why?
求你了爷爷，快回答我? ！
Please, grandpa, why?!
原谅我，孩子
Forgive me, my boy.
我都知道…
I know why...
不然你爷爷就有没有活下去的理由了
so that your grandpa would have a reason to live.
巴尔干半岛的阴影 第一季 第六集
BLACK SUN EPISODE 6
- 早上好亲爱的 - 早上好
- Good morning, my love. - Good morning.
现在几点了？
Good morning. What time is it?
- 是时候了 - 什么时候？
- It's time. - For what?
你遇见什么人了吗？
Whom did you meet?
先别说这些，我赶时间
I can't do this now, I'm in a hurry.
- 你遇到什么人了，告诉我 - 我真的得走了
- You met someone, tell me. - I really have to go.
告诉我，你遇见了谁？
Whom did you meet, tell me?
是的，我遇到了一个人
Yes, I met someone.
我的初恋
My first love.
他说他在城里，所以我去找他
He said he was in town, so I went to see him.
我去了他的公寓
I came to his apartment.
天很黑
It was dark.
突然，有人从背后抱住了我
Suddenly, I felt someone grabbing me,
一只手捂住我的嘴，另一只手搂着我的腰
putting one hand over my mouth and the other around my waist.
我能感受到他的巨龙在我背后摩擦
I felt he had a hard-on.
是他
It was him,
他开始脱我的衣服
he started undressing me,
说他一直在想我
talking how he had been thinking of me,
撕扯我的内裤
and ripping my panties.
- 接着讲 - 突然他带我..
- Talk to me. - Suddenly, he took me...
不要停，继续讲
Talk to me, talk to me more.
我喘不上气了，康斯坦丁
You're choking me, Konstantin.
- 说话啊，亲爱的 - 你掐死我了
- Talk to me, dear. - You're choking me.
- 说话! - 你要掐死我了！
- Talk to me! - You're choking me!
得了吧！
Oh, c'mon!
好像我是个会掐死自己老婆的疯子似的
As if I'm some kind of wacko who chokes his own wife.
对不起，亲爱的，是我的问题
I'm sorry, my love, it's not you.
- 怎么了? - 我很担心玛雅
- What's wrong? - I'm worried about Maya,
恐怕她出了什么事
I'm afraid something has happened to her.
玛雅就像一只猫，她不会有事的
Maya is like a cat, nothing will happen to her.
玛雅在哪里？
Where is Maya?
- 我怎么知道? - 你在这儿干什么？
- How would I know? - What are you doing here?
我在照顾自己
I'm taking care.
玛雅才是你应该照顾的人
You're taking care of Maya, that's what you're doing.
你吃醋了吗？
Are we being jealous?
我再问一遍，玛雅在哪里？
I'll ask again, where's Maya?
我再说一遍，我不知道
I'm telling you I don't know.
我好几天没有她的消息了，你又吸毒了吗？
I haven't heard from her in days. Are you doing drugs again?
你又开始演坏警察了？
We're playing bad cop, again?
检察官先生，我们来看看这起非法闯入事件
We'll see about that break-in, Mr. Prosecutor.
非法入室抢劫
A break-in and a robbery.
- 照照镜子看看谁是窃贼... - 混蛋
- We'll see who's the burglar here... - Thug.
怂货！
Pussy!
别伤到自己，探长，不然我白照顾你了
Don't hurt yourself, inspector, now that I've healed you.
快点，姑娘
Hurry up, girl.
快来，水开始凉了
Here. The water is getting cold.
- 他来了，医生 - 塔内，你这老不死的！
- There he is, doctor. - Tane, you old wreck!
下午好
Good afternoon.
帮我看着衣服
Take care of my clothes, please.
这是什么？
What is it?
我给你带了礼物
I brought you presents.
- 你喝多了? - 没有！
- You've been drinking? - I haven't!
天呐，男人给他的妻子买礼物还要被怀疑
Dear Lord, a man cannot buy his wife a present without looking suspicious
谢谢
Thank you.
塔纳西耶维奇，你在这里玩得很开心
Tanasiyevich, you're having a great time here.
看看你的伤口，正在愈合
Let's look at you. It's healing.
近来可好？
How are you?
浑身疼，至少意味着我还活着
Everything hurts, which means I'm alive.
镇上发生什么事了？
What's going on in the town?
当你躺着的时候，你的同事进行了抓捕行动
While you're lying around, your colleague is making arrests.
三连环杀人犯被捕！
TRIPLE MURDERER ARRESTED!
把你的衣服脱掉
Take your clothes off..
- 为什么? ! - 给你做检查
- Why?! - To examine you.
安静下来，读报纸，深呼吸
Be quiet and read that. Deep breaths.
你应该看到好的一面
You should look at the bright side.
至少我们知道维奥莱塔的死不是因为你
At least we know that Violeta wasn't killed because of you
还有你的底片
and your negatives.
真会安慰人，她已经死了，我差点就被人杀掉
Real comforting. She didn't, but I almost did.
人头乱飞，我该怎么办? 开心吗？
Heads are flying all over and I should just what? Be merry?
我忘了告诉你一件事..
I forgot to tell you something...
如果按照我预期
If this follows the direction I have anticipated,
下一个死的可能是你的情夫
the next in line could be your boy, Djukich.
沃因？
Voyin?
但如果艾林真的是凶手，而他已经被捕…
But if Avram really is the killer and he was arrested...
这案子太复杂了，一个疯子做不到这种程度
This is way too complicated to be the fault of one madman.
那另一个疯子呢，那个和维奥莱塔上床的俄罗斯人？
What about the other madman, the Russian who shagged Violeta?
给她项链的那个？
The one who gave her the necklace?
你似乎知道一些细节
You seem to know the details.
- 你告诉我的 - 不是
- You told me. - No.
我只是问你知不知道维奥莱塔有个情人
I only asked if you knew that Violeta had a lover.
我从没说过是俄罗斯人
I never said it was a Russian, and certainly not
而且绝对没提项链的事情
that he gave her the necklace.
又来审讯，好吧，是沃因告诉我的
Interrogation, again. Okay, Voyin told me that.
他告诉你项链在他手上了吗？
Did he tell you that he has the necklace now?
那个疯子偷了项链，丢了脑袋
The necklace that nutjob stole and lost his head over?
而另一个疯子画项链，然后把人的头砍下来
While the other nutjob painted it and chopped people's heads off.
他没说，我刚听你说才知道的
He did not. I just learned that from you.
好吧，记住了
Well, learn it.
看来这两个疯子毫无共同之处
And it seems that those two nutjobs have nothing in common.
一切都围绕着那条该死的项链
Everything revolves around that fucking necklace.
或者是与之相关的东西
Or something connected with it.
我们现在唯一能做的就是猜测
The only thing we can do now is guess...
谁是下一个被杀的人
who's next in the line to get fucked.
很可能就是那个拿着
And that's probably the one who has the necklace
你那变态朋友画的项链的人
that your creepy friend painted.
好吧，你怎么了？
Alright, what's wrong now?
艾林不是凭空画出项链
Avram did not paint the necklace,
但是上面的标志——耶穌鱼
but the symbol on it. Ichthys – fish.
是一个古老的基督教符号
It is an old Christian symbol.
那幅画是要表达神的死亡
The focus of the painting was the death of God-man.
看来你也知道了
I see you know about that too.
知道什么？
About what?
知道你那个变态画家朋友
About the daubings of that creep of yours
还有项链的样子
and the precise appearance of the necklace.
我知道他的工作
I know his work.
而且我也有机会近距离看到维奥莱塔的项链
And I have had the opportunity to see Violeta's necklace up close.
我不知道有没有人会被杀
And I don't know if someone is going to get fucked,
但我很确定你现在应该从我眼前消失！
but I'm pretty certain you should fuck off right about now!
进来吧
Come in.
探长，女医生来看你了
Inspector, you have a visit. Miss Doctor...
我是不是应该让你们单独聊聊？
Shall I leave the lovebirds alone?
日沃因，我要是智商像你那么低，我直接选择死亡
Zhivoyin, if only I had your brain, it would be a holiday.
请…
Please...
那天晚上你去哪儿了？
Where did you disappear the other night?
如果这就是你来的原因，我很忙
If that's why you came, I'm busy.
- 我没时间 - 但你有时间摆姿势看报纸
- I don't have time. - But you do have the time to pose
那是我能看到你的地方
for newspapers, that's where I can see you.
- 我没有印象 - 什么？
- I didn't get the impression. - What?
- 你想见我 - 那你就创造印象
- That you wanted to see me. - Well, get the impression.
那是什么？
What's that?
我在找一个孩子，他父亲把他带走了
I'm looking for a child. His father took him away,
母亲不记得父亲的名字
and mother doesn't remember the father's name
这充分说明了父亲的人品
That speaks volumes about his qualities.
你有他的出生证明和出生地吗？
Do you have his birth certificate, place of birth?
我有孩子的名字
I have here the names of the child,
还有母亲和孩子爷爷的名字
mother and father's father.
怪不得他们都姓佩塔尔
That's why they are all called Petar.
- 是的 - 是的
- Yes. - Right.
查错方向了，跟我来
Wrong approach. Come with me.
别担心，我不会带你去跳舞的，我只是想帮忙
Don't worry, I'm not taking you dancing. I just want to help.
再见
Goodbye.
他抓住我的乳房！
He grabbed my tits!
- 你撒谎! - 我撒谎? 是你来找我的
- You're lying! - Me, lying? You came to me,
然后开始摸我的乳头! 还有我的屁股！
and started groping my tits! And my bottom, too!
给我一公斤草莓我都不会和你做爱！
I wouldn't fuck you for a kilo of strawberries!
做梦吧你！
You couldn't even if you wanted to!
安静！
Be quiet!
莫德林，我已经告诉过你了..
Maudlin, I've already told you...
如果想做爱，你就得付钱
If you want to fuck, you have to pay.
- 明白了吗? - 你们两个都去死吧！
- Is that clear? - Fuck off, both of you!
你在看什么? 回去工作！
What are you looking at? Get back to work!
你能不能把你这破吧台擦一擦！
Can you clean up this mess once in your life!
如果你嫌脏，拿一块布自己擦干净
Take a cloth and clean it up yourself if it bothers you.
如果我是你，我就不会这么鲁莽
Look, I wouldn't be so brash if I were you.
但你不是
But you're not.
- 什么? - 你不是我
- What? - You're not me.
你知道裁缝不在吧，你知道现在谁是老大吗？
You know that Tailor's away? You do. And who's in charge now?
谁？
Who?
我! 明白了吗？
I am! Is that clear?
听着，斯塔夫拉，别惹泰勒
Listen, Stavra, don't mess with Tailor.
他是独一无二的
There's no one like him.
那不重要! 我需要你为我做件事
Svejedno! It doesn't matter! I need you to do something for me.
过来，孩子！
Come here, boy!
这个马其顿人想在报纸上登广告
This Macedonian fellow wants to put a newspaper ad.
你要带他去
And you're gonna help him
因为他不熟悉城里的路
because he doesn't know his way around town.
你在干什么？
What are you doing?
- 读上面的字 - 你为什么在乎上面写什么？
- Reading. - Why do you care what it says?
- 你是对的，我不在乎 - 来吧，带他去邮局
- You're right, I don't. - C'mon, take him to the post office.
莫德林，看好这个地方，别把我的白兰地都喝光了
Maudlin, keep an eye on the place and don't drink all of my brandy.
- 好吧，安塔，别担心 - 你叫什么名字？
- Alright, Anta, don't worry. - What's your name?
- 安吉尔斯 - 我的天…
- Angelce. - Sweet baby Jesus...
快点，走吧
C'mon, move it.
国家能处决一个严重精神错乱的人吗？
Can the state execute a seriously deranged man?
永恒的道德困境
The eternal moral dilemma.
也许州政府不能决定，但如果由我决定..
Maybe the state cannot, but if it were up to me...
家族中没有精神病史
No history of mental illnesses in the family,
大量使用酒精，鸦片，大麻..
extensive use of alcohol, opiates, hashish...
奈斯托维奇先生，大麻！
Mr. Nestorovich, hashish!
艺术和大麻是紧密相连的
Art and hashish go hand in hand.
你们打他了吗？
Did you beat him?
绝对没有，你知道我们不打囚犯的
Absolutely not. You know we do not beat the prisoners.
我知道所以才问你
I know, that's why I'm asking.
当普莱蒂科西奇督察在审问他的时候
While Inspector Pletikosich was questioning him,
他说话语无伦次，还引用了
he talked incoherently and quoted
马可福音
the Bible, the Gospel according to Mark.
福音? ，奈斯托维奇先生! 为什么是福音？
The Gospel? Mr. Nestorovich! Why the Gospel?
你还没有失去信仰，是吗？
You haven't lost your faith, have you?
我得说他现在没心情聊天
I'd say he's not in the mood for a chat.
处于这种状态的人通常都不想跟人说话
People in such a state usually aren't.
- 你是说疯了? - 不不
- You mean crazy? - No, no.
不，不，他的道德轴心和对现实的感知有点错位
No, no, his moral axis and perception of reality are slightly misplaced,
但不至于让他意识不到自己的罪行
but not to the extent that would make him unaware of his crimes.
- 他可以接受审判吗? - 可以
- Can he stand trial? - Yes.
这些药每天给他两次，直到审判
Give him these pills twice a day, until the trial.
- 我们现在能走了吗... - 好的
- Can we leave now, please... - Yes.
- 住手，你疯了! - 怎么了？
- Stop it, you're crazy! - Stop what?
- 快住手，我要告诉你点事 - 我知道你要告诉我什么
- Stop, I need to tell you something. - I know what you need to tell me.
- 不，真的，这很重要 - 来吧，事情可以等
- No, really, it's important. - Come on, it can wait.
- 你干什么? - 对不起，亲爱的
- What is it? - I'm sorry, my love,
有个疯子在外面要杀我朋友，我真的不能做爱
I really can't fuck while some lunatic is out there, beheading my friend.
- 什么疯子，什么朋友? - 玛雅，我的玛雅
- What lunatic, what friend? - Maya, my Maya.
我跟你说过她
I told you about her.
疯子是那个砍头的人
And the lunatic is the one cutting off heads.
好吧
Okay.
但是她和这有什么关系呢？
But what does she have to do with it?
那个疯子杀了维奥莱塔
Well, the wacko killed Violeta.
事实上，他是冲着玛雅来的
Actually, he was after Maya.
维奥莱塔和玛雅订了同样的衣服
Violeta and Maya ordered the same dress.
现在他们知道杀错人了，一定会找玛雅
Now they want to correct the mistake and are looking for Maya,
都是因为那些该死的照片
all because of those fucking photos.
什么照片？
What photos?
我不知道，但她想把照片给你
I don't know. She wanted to give them to you,
这样你就可以一起勒索那个人，她想拯救银行
so you can blackmail them together. She wanted to save the bank.
勒索谁？
To blackmail whom?
日夫科维奇将军
General Zhivkovich.
该死! 现在听我说
Bloody hell! Listen to me now.
冷静下来，告诉我一切
Calm down and tell me everything.
所有细节，你明白吗？
Everything, do you understand?
- 昨晚生意不错吧? - 一般
- It was a good night, wasn't it? - Not that good.
一般？
Not that good?
我还以为警察更有钱呢
I thought fucking cops is worth more.
- 我不明白 - 你不明白什么？
- I don't understand. - What you don't understand?
好吧，把你的手套洗了
Okay, wash your muff,
我要带你出城去见有钱的客户
I'm taking you out of town to wealthy clients.
听着，斯塔夫拉，你知道我不做上门的生意
Listen, Stavra, you know I can't leave this place just like that.
- 斯塔夫拉，不要! - 闭嘴！
- Stavra, don't! - Shut up!
把我昨晚赚的钱都拿去
Take all the money I made last night.
你赚的? 你现在成了警察的线人吧，臭婊子！
Made? Cops gave it to you to be their snitch, bitch!
不... 没人给我什么好处，这些钱你都拿走，我不要了！
No... No one gave me anything, take everything. I don't need it!
拿去吧，我不需要！
Take it, I don't need it!
你什么都不要，很好，我会牢记你的话
You don't need anything. You're lucky I'm a man of his word.
真乖... 这是为了你好
That's it... This is for your own good.
好久不见，室友？
How's it going, roomie?
好久不见啊，土耳其人？
How's it going, Turk?
- 你为什么打我的人? - 去你妈的，还有你小弟！
- Why did you beat my men? - Fuck you and your security!
如果我想让你死，你早就死了
If I wanted you dead, you'd be dead already.
- 什么风把你吹来了? - 来参观我的单身房间
- Why did you come here? - To visit my bachelor room.
还要见见我的室友
And to see my roommate.
著名的黑手党，前黑手党成员
The famous Black Hand. Former Black Hand.
据我所知，你也是前黑手党成员
As far as I can recall, you're also a former Black Hand.
是的，只不过我还在为统一而战
Yeah. Except that I'm still fighting for the unification,
而你只面对死亡
while you only deal with death.
我不知道阿皮斯和坦科耶奇对"统一"是什么看法
I'm not sure what Apis and Tankosich would say about that new unification.
坦科耶奇至少会割掉我的耳朵，还有你的
Tankosich would, at the very least, cut off my ear. And yours.
可不是吗
That's what I'm telling you.
但是阿皮斯会理解我的，至于你，我就不那么确定了
However, Apis would understand me. But you, I'm not so sure.
你是来对我说教的吗？
Did you come here to lecture me?
说教有什么用
That'd be futile.
我猜你在贝尔格莱德应该还有比这更适合你的地方吧
I'm guessing there's a better place for you in Belgrade than this?
你大老远从莫斯科过来
And that you didn't come all the way from Moscow
- 就为了见你的老朋友? - 别这样
- Just to see your old mate? - Don't be like that.
你需要什么帮助吗？
So, you need something?
- 某种程度上是的 - 说吧
- In a way. - Speak.
当年你杀了那个害死你妻子的医生…
That boss of yours, who got you out of prison
你老板把你从监狱捞出来
when you killed the doctor responsible for your wife's death...
他们说你对他忠心耿耿
They say you're loyal to him like a dog.
就像你对那个死于梅毒
The same way you're loyal to that bearded fella who died of syphilis,
and did nothing to deserve your loyalty.
而且浪得虚名的胡须男一样忠心
有人说他知道贝尔格莱德所有人的一切秘密
They say he knows everything about everyone in Belgrade.
是的
He does.
那他应该知道是谁在找那个叛徒的破照片了
Then he knows who's looking for fag photos of that traitor.
什么叛徒？
What traitor?
你知道那个背叛我们的混蛋
You know the piece of shit who betrayed us.
帕蒂萨，那个同性恋
Peritza, the faggot.
那他一定知道是谁因为那些照片
Well, then he must know who kidnapped a nice lady
绑架了一位美丽的女士
because of those photos.
有可能
It's possible.
那就告诉他，我准备好用金子换照片了
Then tell him I'm ready to pay for those photos in gold,
如果这位女士少了一根头发
and that I will cut his eyes out
我会把绑匪的眼睛挖出来
if a single hair is missing from the lady's head.
你知道我不是说说而已
You know I'm not just saying it.
过几天你就会知道答案了
You'll get the answers in a few days.
但是说到这位女士
But, when it comes to the lady,
恐怕你得把某个情人的眼睛挖出来
I'm afraid you'll have to cut out the eyes of some lover.
好吧，你就把我说的话告诉他，我不想出现任何问题
Okay, you just tell him what I said. I don't want any problems later on.
- 就这么定了 - 保重，兄弟
- Consider it done. - Take care, mate.
你好（土耳其语）
Merhaba.
你跟别人打招呼的时候才说"Merhaba"
You say merhaba when you greet someone,
他们走的时候不行，你这个无知的混蛋
not when they're leaving, you ignorant fuck.
我才不管什么时候该说什么
Mustapha, I don't give a rat's ass about when and what is said.
我也是
Me neither.
你把我们打得落花流水，黑山人
You beat the hell out of us, Montenegrin.
我不是黑山人
I'm not from Montenegro.
- 好吧，波斯尼亚人? - 不，也不是波斯尼亚人
- Okay, Bosnian? - No, not from Bosnia either.
- 那你是哪里人? - 黑塞哥维那
- So, where are you from? - From Herzegovina.
没关系，我给她吸了一点那个... 叫什么来着? 叶绿素
It's okay, we gave her this... what's it called? Chlorophyll.
你还打了她一顿
I see you gave her a beating too.
我必须打她，她反抗了
Well, I had to, she put up a fight.
嘿，她的身材很棒，谁会在意那些淤青？
Hey, she's got good tits, nice ass, who's gonna look at the bruises?
- 我什么时候来接她? - 不用接了
- When should I pick her up?  - She's not your problem anymore.
如果有人问起她，你最好什么都不知道
If someone asks for her, it's better if you know nothing.
这是给你的
Here's something for your trouble.
伯爵向你的老板问好，带她过去
Count sends greetings to your boss. Take her out.
照顾好自己，没事回来看看，别像个陌生人
Take care of yourself and come for a visit, don't be a stranger.
- 我会的，谢谢你 - 斯米利亚，快让他们上路吧！
- I will, thank you. - Smilya, don't hold them up!
我想再和我弟弟多待一会儿
I'm going to hold up my brother as much as I want to,
谁知道我什么时候能再见到他！
Only God knows when I'll see him again!
斯米利亚，谢谢你... 你让我感觉像在家一样
Smilya, thank you... you made me feel like at home.
小心点，别让我弟弟因为你而死
Watch it, don't let my brother die because of you.
谁会死? 别瞎说
Who's gonna die? What are you talking about?
我告诉过你一百次了，管好你自己的事
I've told you a hundred times, mind your own business.
好吧
Alright.
你有没有告诉玛雅小姐
Did you tell Miss Maya about that time
你在桶里渡过萨瓦河的时候？
when you crossed the Sava in a barrel?
只说了一百万次，可以吗？
Only about a million times. Shall we?
- 你就继续开玩笑吧 - 我们走
- Just you keep joking around. - Let's go.
普尔沙，我们走吧
Prsho, let's go!
- 保重! - 我们走了，美女
- Take care! - Let's go, beautiful.
旅途愉快，欢迎再来！
Have a nice trip and come again!
塞尔维亚南部 警察检查站
POLICE CHECKPOINT VRANJE, SOUTHERN SERBIA
南斯拉夫王国
Kingdom of Serbs, Croats and Slovenes
让我过去！
Hey, let me pass!
放松，例行检查
Easy, control first.
我要迟到了，朋友，别这样
I'm late, my friend, please don't.
这次你怎么没有报告有其他种类的货物呢？
You didn't report having different kind of goods this time?
拜托! 她姨妈死了，我要带她去贝尔格莱德
Come on! Her aunt died, I'm taking her to Belgrade.
女士方便下车吗？
Can the miss step outside?
别... 等等... 她..
Don't... No, wait... She's...
等一下，她是我从库马诺沃来的表妹
Wait a minute, she's my cousin from Kumanovo.
闭嘴! 她不会说话吗？
Shut up! Can she speak?
你叫什么名字，姑娘？
What's your name, girl?
大哥，给你钱
C'mon, man, take the money,
和你的同事分了，让我们过去，快点，我们要迟到了
split it with your colleague and let us pass. Come on, we're late.
我会让她过去的
I'd let her pass through my hands.
把钱放回你的口袋里！
Put that money back in your pocket!
可以用她来付小费，对吧？
She could pay in services, right?
拜托，大哥，她是我表妹！
Come on, man, she's my cousin!
那就更好了，自产自销
That's even better. You'll keep it in the family.
看看这个，车上可不只有妓女
Look at this! There's more here than just the whore?
- 这可怎么办呢? - 等等，听我说
- What are we gonna do now? - Wait, listen to me.
都拿去吧，我只有这些了，别浪费时间了
Take all of it, it's all I got, stop messing around.
- 让我们过去，我们要迟到了 - 我知道，但是我的同事说..
- Let us pass, man, we're late. - I know, but my colleague said...
我们想和你表妹做点什么..
that we would like a little something with your cousin...
就一点点..
Just a little...
你是哪里人，美女？
Where are you from, beautiful?
这个女孩话不多
The girl doesn't talk much.
但她一定很会吸，对吧？
But she's good at sucking, right?
谢谢你
Thank you.
再见
Goodbye.
再见，探长
So long, inspector.
上帝与我们同在
nobiscum Deus
- 你找到了? - 是的
- You found it? - Yes.
给我看看! 给我看看！
Show it to me! Show it!
朱基奇先生
Mr. Djukich...
我永远感激你! 永远！
You have my eternal gratitude! Eternal!
萨沙，倒酒，快请坐
Sasha, vodka! Please, have a seat. Please.
你知道..
You know...
他们夺走了我们的一切
They took everything from us.
土地，权力
Land, power given by God.
不仅如此，我们的家庭、人生…
And not only that. Our families, lives...
甚至把上帝也从我们身边夺走
They took God away from us.
如果我们的国王没有一开始就禁止共产主义
If our king hadn't banned the communists at the very beginning,
这里现在也会是一样
the same thing would have happened here.
人们挨饿的时候会立马投靠共产党
People quickly turn red when they are hungry.
萨沙
Sasha...
俄罗斯..
Russia...
永远欠你的人情，朱基奇先生
will eternally be in your debt, Mr. Djukich.
- 干杯 - 干杯！
- Cheers! - Cheers!
请帮我接2246
Please, connect me to 2246.
- 打扰一下，女士 - 什么事
- Excuse me, ma'am. - Yes.
有客人来了
You have a visitor.
玛雅！
Maya!
你还活着! 这段时间你都去哪儿了？
You're alive! Where've you been all this time?
我以为你的头也被人砍下来了
I thought you died, that your head was chopped off,
躺在沟里，浑身是血
that you were lying in some ditch, covered in blood.
这事还没结束，我还不能回家
This doesn't end. I can't even go home.
我该怎么办？
What am I supposed to do?
别担心
Don't worry.
我来告诉你怎么做
I'll tell you what to do.
但是记住，你不能向任何人提起他的名字
But keep in mind, you can't ever mention his name to anyone.
咱们俩谁是大嘴巴？
Who's a blabbermouth here, you or me?
贝尔格莱德这鬼地方，到处都买不到羽衣甘蓝
Damn Belgrade, I can't find collard greens anywhere.
不管怎样，达维多维奇小姐，我知道为什么克里斯塔要把你藏起来了
Anyhow, Miss Davidovich, I can see why Krista hid you
你的美貌很难掩饰
from her Muyo. It's difficult to hide such beauty.
所以我不明白她为什么把你带到我这里
That's why I don't understand why she is handing you to me.
我在开玩笑! 我聪明的克丽丝塔知道我有自知之明
I'm joking, relax! My clever Krista knows I know my place.
好吧，你打算告诉她为什么来这里了吗？
Alright. Are you going to tell her something about the reason she came?
没什么好担心的
You've nothing to worry about.
你可以回家了
Miss can go home, Muyo remains yours.
- 什么意思? - 我是说你可以回家了
- How do you mean? - I mean you can go home.
你觉得我安全了吗？
You think I'm safe?
他们已经拿走了项链
They took the necklace.
没有理由再追杀你
They have no reason to come after you.
你确定吗？
Are you sure about that?
人们总是说我对我的工作很在行
There are people who think I'm good at this.
但是，朱基奇先生还给你别的东西了吗？
But, did Mr. Djukich give you anything else?
你怎么知道项链是他给我的？
And you're absolutely certain I got it from him?
人们说我也很擅长这个
People say I'm good at that too.
他只给了我项链
He only gave me the necklace.
那就没问题了
Then there's no problem.
如果他给了你别的东西，你就不安全了
If he gave you something else with it, you're not safe.
你自己看吧
See for yourself.
好吧，如果项链不在我这里就是安全的话
Okay, if I'm safe without the necklace,
那么谢谢你的帮助，我终于可以回家了
then I thank you for your help. I can finally go home.
谢天谢地！
Thank God!
我能问问你... 那些照片是怎么处理的？
Can I ask you... What happened to the photos?
我不得不把底片给他们
I had to give the negatives.
底片是一回事，照片是另一回事
Negatives are one thing, the photos are another.
我想，也许还有一些照片放在什么地方了？
I thought, maybe some got misplaced?
不幸的是，没有
None, unfortunately.
如果有的话，我早就给你了
If they had, I'd have given them to you.
真可惜
Pity.
以防万一，我会找人在你家附近暗中保护你
I'll have someone to watch the house, just in case.
现在你的资产阶级味觉，将尝到穆斯塔法经常吃的一餐
Now your bourgeois palates will taste a meal Mustapha was raised on.
你觉得怎么样？
What do you say, huh?
他怎么还没到？
How come he's not there yet?
什么意思，我这国防部还是妓院？
What is this, a defence ministry or a brothel?
告诉立马给我回电话，明白了吗？
Tell him to call me as soon as he gets in, is that clear?
- 又怎么了? - 阿里姆皮耶 · 米里奇想见你
- What do you want now? - Alimpiye Mirich wants to see you.
我不是说过我再也不想见到他了吗？
Didn't I say I never want to see him again?
他已经等了两个小时了
He has been waiting for two hours now.
他说，这个国家的命运岌岌可危
He says the fate of the country is at stake.
- 好吧，带他进来 - 是，长官！
- Okay. Bring him in. - Yes, sir!
- 米里奇 - 将军
- Mirich. - General, sir.
这个我一无所知的国家危险是什么？
What is this danger that I know nothing about, huh?
将军，什么是国家？
Sir, what is the state?
是土地，人民，议会，还是权利？
Is it the country, people, assembly, crown?
米里奇…
Mirich...
国家是一艘由少数杰出人士驾驶的船
The state is a ship navigated by a few exceptional people,
当他们中的一些人处于危险之中，船就会沉没
and when some of them are in danger, the ship could sink.
是谁有危险，米里奇？
Who is in danger, Mirich?
是你，将军
You, general sir.
真的吗？
Really?
为什么这么说？
How so?
您误会我了，证据在这里
Let me show you the proof that you misunderstood me.
将军，我不是来勒索您的
Sir, this is not a case of blackmail.
还有复印件吗？
Are there any more copies?
只要这幕后的人仍然逍遥法外
We can't be sure,
我们就无法确定
as long as the man from whom they were taken is at large.
那个人是谁？
And who is that man?
你的一个熟人，有很多名字
An acquaintance of yours, known under many names,
其中一个名字就是穆斯塔法
one of which is Mustapha.
- 我可以坐下吗? - 不行
- I suppose I can sit? - You can not.
快点，你还有什么要说的
Quickly, say what you have to say.
穆斯塔法是挂在你脖子上的恶魔
Mustapha is an evil hanging around your neck,
而我是那个可以让恶魔消失的人
and I'm the one who could make it go away.
然后你想要垄断作为回报，对吗？
And get the monopoly in return, right?
是的，但为了让垄断有意义
Yes. But for it to make sense,
你必须除掉一支非法军队的将军
you'd have to get rid of the general
和他的鸦片兄弟
of an illegal army and his opium brethren.
那么，你把我从少校手里救出来，我把你从将军手里救出来？
So, you free me from the major, and I free you from the general?
你是不是有点过分了？
Aren't you a bit out of line?
别忘了少校身后
Don't forget that behind the major
还有一支更大的军队没有被放逐
there's a much larger army which is not in exile.
他准备用这支军队为他的私利来对付你
And he's ready to use it against you for his own personal reasons.
我还想提醒你们，不仅沃兰赫尔将军
I would also like to remind you that not only General Vrangel
不是你的朋友，更是你的敌人
is not your friend, he is your enemy.
自从你不再付钱给他，他就一直在背着你做事
He's been going behind your back ever since you stopped paying him.
所以我的提议不仅仅是交易
That's why my proposition is not a mere trade,
你把我从我的敌人手中救出来
where you'd save me from my enemies,
我会把你从你敌人手里拯救出来
and I'd save you from yours.
不，我的提议是联盟
No. My proposal is an alliance
对抗我们共同的两个敌人:
against our two common enemies:
红军与白军
The Reds and the Whites.
- 请坐，米里奇先生 - 谢谢
- Please, take a seat, Mr. Mirich. - Thank you.
塔尼，是谁把你打成这样的？
Tane, who did this to you?
一个吃醋的丈夫
A jealous husband.
- 一大群丈夫? - 是的，一大群
- A multitude of husbands? - A battalion of them.
好了，别哭哭啼啼了，给我来杯咖啡
C’mon, stop whining. Bring me a cup of coffee.
督察
Inspector.
新闻界的大英雄，你替代了我的位置？
Hero of the press, you took my spot?
你当我塔尼死了？
You thought Tane was gone?
我去贫民窟找过你，先生
I was looking for you in the slum, sir.
我听说了，别再叫我先生
I heard that. And stop calling me sir.
你去看医生了吗？
Did you see a doctor?
没有，但我想去看看你的医生
No, but I'd like to visit that doctor of yours.
- 谁? - 赖斯博士，给他打电话
- Who? - Dr. Reiss. Call him.
你逮捕画家的那天
That day when you arrested the painter,
他打电话给你，说有消息要告诉你
he called you and said he had some information for you.
好吧，但案子已经结了
Yeah, but the case is closed.
结个屁! 打电话给他！
It's closed my ass! Call him!
你疯了吗? 你在干什么？
Are you crazy? What are you doing?
- 他们会永远把我关起来的 - 这不是我能决定的
- They'll close me for good. - It's not up to me.
谁来喝我的酒？
Who's gonna drink my booze?
- 都是因为白兰地... - 放松，尼什基
- It's all because of cognac... - Relax, Nishky.
快点，给他泼醒！
Come on, pour water over him!
- 嘿，特纳瓦茨，这位是新来的小妞吗? - 安静！
- Hey, Trnavatz, is that a new chick? - Be quiet!
小心丢了你的蛋！
Or you'll lose your balls!
为了这么漂亮的美人，丢就丢了
I'd lose them for a beauty like this.
可以安排一下
It can be arranged.
天啊！
Jesus!
她来了，老板
There she is, boss.
基拉老大
Boss Kira.
看来你在贝尔格莱德过得挺滋润呢
I see you found your way around Belgrade.
下午好，尤瓦娜，路上顺利吗？
Good afternoon, Yovana. Have you travelled well?
太他妈顺利了！
Damn well!
滚
Well, fuck it.
请坐
Please, take a seat.
旅途愉快吗？
Have you travelled well?
嗯，非常好
Yes, we have. Really well.
但是现在这已经不重要了
But that doesn't matter now.
重要的是你告诉我
What matters is for you to tell me
为什么我弟弟还在监狱里？
why my brother is still in jail?
你想吃点什么吗？
Do you want to eat something?
- 嘿，老板? - 嗯？
- Hey boss? - Huh?
需要什么？
What do you want?
老板的杜松子酒很好喝
Ante has a killer schnapps.
看来贝尔格莱德的杜松子酒已经浸入你的大脑了
Looks like that Belgrade schnapps has gotten into your head.
什么贝尔格莱德杜松子酒？
What Belgrade schnapps?
那是顶级的私酿烈酒
This is a top quality moonshine.
- 你是安东尼对吧？ - 对
- Antonie, right? - Yep.
滚远点，安东尼
Fuck off, Antonie.
你没看见我们正在谈话吗！
Can't you see we're having a conversation here!
不要就不要，这么凶！
No schnapps then. God forbid!
你有什么好消息要告诉我吗？
Do you have something clever to tell me?
我看得出你在这里过得很自在
I can see you feel quite at home here.
你打算怎么救我弟弟？
What is the plan for Damyan?
你不用担心这个，会有人处理的
Don't you worry about Damyan. It's going to be taken care of.
- 什么时候? - 明天
- When? - Tomorrow
我应该相信你的话吗？
And I should just take your word for it?
听着，尤瓦娜
Look, Yovana.
我是从布科沃来的
I came here from Bukovo.
我花了很多钱
I spent a ton of money.
就目前的情况来看，我还得付出更多
And as things stand, I'll have to give a ton more.
我必须和这些贝尔格莱德的白痴好好相处,
I have to play nice with these Belgrade dickheads,
因为他们想接管生意
and get fucked because they want to take over the business.
我现在最不需要的就是你教训我
The last thing I need is you lecturing me right now.
我说过我会把你弟弟救出来的
I told you I would get your brother out of the hole,
我说到做到
and that's exactly what's going to happen.
现在，你想喝点什么？
Now, what are you drinking?
好吧，给我们来一瓶顶级的杜松子酒
Well then, give us that famous schnapps.
- 我听说很不错 - 老板！
- I've heard it's really good. - Boss!
请出示您的身份证件
Can I see your ID cards, please?
谢谢，让我们搜查一下
Thank you. Let's have you searched.
你好，哈吉先生
Good day, Mr. Hadzhi-Arsov.
想抽根烟吗？
You want a cigarette?
- 我知道你在生我的气 - 没错
- I see you're mad at me. - I am.
还气我自己，因为我是个混蛋
At myself too. For being such a jackass.
你的朋友向你问好
Your friend sends his greetings.
看报纸，广告，倒数第二页
Read the papers. Ads, the page next-to-last.
你现在想抽烟了吗？
Would you like a cigarette now?
再见
See you.
阿廖沙做错了什么
How can Alyosha be guilty
当他在监狱里的时候内文也被杀了
when he was in prison when Neven was killed?
是他杀了牧师
He killed the priest.
他抢劫了祭坛并偷走了项链
He robbed the altar and stole the necklace.
牧师看到了他，一切就这样开始了
The priest saw him. That's how it all began.
艾林看到了沃因·朱基奇的项链
And Avram saw the necklace on Violeta Djukich.
所以他杀了维奥莱塔，然后杀了内文
So he killed her and then Neven.
而阿廖沙显然是被自己人杀死的
While Alyosha was obviously killed by one of his own.
那我们报告里怎么写？
How are we supposed to put that in our report?
去他妈的报告，逻辑才是最重要的
Screw the report. It's what's logical that counts.
项链看起来很重要
The necklace seems pretty important.
赖斯博士告诉我他四处打听过
Reiss told me he had asked around.
- 先生，油加满了 - 谢谢，我们走吧
- Sir, the tank is full. - Thank you, let's go.
请进，教授，非常感谢
Please, come in. Professor, thank you very much.
这位是..
This is...
我认识督察，你的战争还没结束吗？
Yes, I know the inspector. You're still battling?
- 你好，博士，别来无恙 - 我还没祝贺你呢
- Hello, doctor, how are you? - I haven't congratulated you
- 你第一次被捕时 - 谢谢
- on your first arrest. - Thank you.
凶手很有意思
Your killer is very interesting.
在审讯过程中
During the interrogation,
艾林引用马可福音:
Avram quoted Gospel according to Mark:
军团是我的名字，因为我们人数众多
Legion is my name, because we are many.
我们认为艾林不是单独作案
We think that Avram wasn't alone,
项链在某种程度上非常重要
and that the necklace is somehow very important.
我问过项链的事
I asked about the necklace.
当我看到罗曼诺夫的徽章时，一切都变得清晰起来
When I saw the stamp of Romanovs, everything became very clear.
这条项链属于亚历山德拉·费奥多罗芙娜皇后
The necklace belonged to the Empress Alexandra,
但不是为她量身定做的
but it wasn't made for her.
- 因为它更古老 - 多古老？
- Because it was much older. - How much older?
几个世纪之前，是这样…
- Centuries. - Look...
看，这是耶稣鱼
Look, this is fish - ichthys.
但是当你转动它的时候，它会让你想到什么？
But when you turn it, what does it remind you of?
长矛头
A head of a lance.
不是普通的长矛，而是朗基努斯的长矛
Not just any lance, but the Lance of Longinus.
你知道圣朗基努斯的故事吗？
Do you know the story about Saint Longinus?
当然
Of course.
朗基努斯是一个罗马军团，他帮助基督摆脱了痛苦
Longinus was a Roman legionary who put Christ out of his agony
用长矛刺向各各他
on Golgotha by stabbing him with the lance,
然后血和水从伤口涌出
after which blood and water gushed out from the wound.
没错
That's right.
这足以让一些人相信
It was enough for some people to believe
长矛拥有巨大的力量
that the lance holds an enormous power.
因为它不仅杀死了基督这个人
Because it killed not only Christ the man,
也杀死了上帝
but Christ the Lord.
这跟项链有什么关系？
And what does the necklace have to do with it?
项链和长矛总是在一起
The necklace and the lance always go together.
有很多关于长矛的故事
There are many stories about the lance, and many lances,
但最有说服力的是康斯坦丁大帝
But the most convincing one is about Emperor Constantine,
拜占庭的开国皇帝
the founder of Byzantium.
传说他的母亲海伦娜皇后
His mother, Empress Helena, as the legend goes,
找到了基督被钉死的十字架
found the cross on which Christ was crucified.
她把三个十字架上的楔子
She brought to Constantinople the three wedges
带到了君士坦丁堡
with which Christ was crucified.
第一个楔子打造了王冠
The first was built into the crown,
第二枪楔子打造了长矛头，第三个楔子融化后
the second into the head of a lance, and the third was melted.
其中的一部分锻造了一把剑
One part of it was used to forge the blade of a sword,
另一个部分做成了项链
and the other to make a necklace.
康斯坦丁如果身边不带着长矛，剑和王冠
Constantine didn't go anywhere without the three sacred items:
这三样神圣的东西哪儿也不去
the lance, the sword and the crown.
海伦娜皇后戴着这条项链
Empress Helen wore the necklace
保护了她和整个帝国
which protected her and the empire.
以及其他拥有项链的统治者
And any other ruler who owned it,
受到上帝的保护
was protected by God.
好吧，但是俄国人和这些有什么关系？
Okay, but what do the Russians have to do with all that?
俄罗斯在历史，宗教和神秘的意义上
Russia is the successor to Byzantium,
是拜占庭的继承者
in historical, religious, and mystical sense.
君士坦丁堡的陷落之后
After the fall of Constantinople,
这些物品被送到莫斯科，留在皇室家族
the items were sent to Moscow and stayed with the Imperial family
直到十月革命，它们就消失得无影无踪
until the October Revolution when they disappeared without a trace.
你认为长矛现在在贝尔格莱德？
And you think the lance is now here in Belgrade?
有可能是俄国人带着宝藏逃走的
It's possible that the Russians brought the treasure when they fled.
这就能解释那些谋杀案了
That would explain the murders.
是的，但是... 凶手是什么人？
Yes, but... Who does the killings?
人们沉迷于对权力的渴望
People. Obsessed with the lust for power.
他们沉迷于寻找遗迹
And in their obsession, they search for the relics,
那是权力的象征
that are the symbols of power.
他们是什么人？
And who are they?
那些人挑起了战争
The ones who start wars,
签署和平条约
sign peace treaties,
推翻政府
overthrow governments,
建立新的政权
install new regimes.
他们生活在阴影中，行动在阴影中
They live and act in the shadows.
因为在我们科学的阴影下，潜伏着魔法
Because from the shadows of our science, lurks magic.
法律的阴影下隐藏着野蛮
Barbarism is hidden behind the shadow of law.
偶像崇拜隐藏在文化的阴影之下
Idolatry is hidden behind the shadow of culture.
人道主义的阴影下还有残酷在等待着我们
Cruelty awaits behind the shadow of humanism.
在黑暗中，有一只手想要抓住长矛…
And in that darkness, there's a hand that wants to grab that lance...
想要获取力量
and get the power.
但在此之前，它必须浸泡在血液中
But before that, it has to dip it in blood.
我确信艾林属于
I'm certain that Avram belongs...
一个这样的神秘组织
to one such occult organisation.
我不知道是哪个，但从项链来看
I don't know which one, but judging by the necklace,
这些人..
these people...
这些人在寻找朗基努斯之矛
these people are looking for the Lance of Longinus.